<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Dives into research, opinion, ideas, and resources. on Worldwide Stew</title>
    <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deep Dives into research, opinion, ideas, and resources. on Worldwide Stew</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 Worldwide Stew, aka Michael Davis.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 16:44:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When industry focuses on human inadequacies</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2025-12-28-when-industry-focuses-on-human-inadequacies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 16:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2025-12-28-when-industry-focuses-on-human-inadequacies/</guid>
      <description>This post originated with the creation of a blog post on New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolutions. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to keep my blog area focused on inspiration. So, instead of posting this in that area, I&amp;rsquo;m adding it to my website&amp;rsquo;s opinion section.
Yesterday, on my blog, I suggested some reasons that resolution brain lets us down:
It fixates on our failures, deficits, and weaknesses It promotes suffering by triggering loss of hope and depression when resolutions fail It highlights our sense of not enough: we don&amp;rsquo;t have enough, we aren&amp;rsquo;t enough, and incites the Hungry Ghost of wanting more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gavin Newsome on the Trump Administration and Democracy</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2025-06-13-gavin-newsome-on-the-trump-administration-and-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2025-06-13-gavin-newsome-on-the-trump-administration-and-democracy/</guid>
      <description>When I started Worldwide Stew, I intended the Blog area of the site to be generally positive in tone. I would reserve the Opinion area of the site for news and opinions about science, health, politics, and fun stuff.
And then we ended up with what can only be called a fascist Administration(Merriam-Webster definition at the link). At this point, the scaffolding that held up any form of democracy is quickly eroding, like hurricane-force winds along the shoreline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Public Media</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2025-06-11-save-public-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 01:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2025-06-11-save-public-media/</guid>
      <description>If you live in the United States and can read this text, it&amp;rsquo;s possible that you learned some reading on Sesame Street. As you got older, you might have watched an episode of the science program Nova. As an adult, you may have watched news programming on the Evening News Hour. While it is fair to say that PBS coverage does tend to lean left of center; unlike other network news, however, PBS makes a concerted effort to fairly cover multiple sides of the issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: August 2024</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-09-04-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-09-04-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m trying to catch up on politics, research articles I&amp;rsquo;ve paid attention to in the last month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: Suicide Crisis Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-05-19-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-05-19-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>There are many methods of screening for suicide risk. The idea of the Suicide Crisis Syndrome appeals to me. It argues that depression or anxiety don&amp;rsquo;t explain all suicide experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: AI, sleep, medical errors, Zionism, peace, and Passover</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-04-28-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-04-28-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>Nurses protest use of AI; the importance of personal and cultural reconsideration on the importance of sleep; prosecution of medical errors; and Zionism and the Passover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: phone addictions; private equity and hospitals</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-02-17-deep-dive-phone-addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-02-17-deep-dive-phone-addiction/</guid>
      <description>This week’s featured articles
From Harvard Business Review. Do you have a phone addiction? - uhh, probably. Now, do something about it. What happens when hospitals aren’t appropriately funded? They often turn to funding from Private Equity firms. What happens then? It’s not good and costs patients and society. Read this article from Harvard. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: Revisiting the work of chaplains</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-02-04-deep-dive-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-02-04-deep-dive-copy/</guid>
      <description>I worry about the relevance of chaplains in mode</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: A questionable iOS feature; US Disease Burden from plastics; interesting recent articles</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-01-28-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-01-28-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>A review of news I find interesting. 1. An iOS &lt;em&gt;feature&lt;/em&gt; you might want to fix. 2. It&amp;rsquo;s taken a long time for plastics to create what many believe will create significant human disease burden. That ship has gathered substantial steam. 3. Possiblle harms related to mindfulness (if your going to be in a mindfulness group, make sure the leader is qualified). 4. Watch out for marketing using &lt;em&gt;neuro&lt;/em&gt;: they may be trying to get into your head. 5. A compassion therapy that can boost &lt;em&gt;expansiveness&lt;/em&gt;? That just blows my mind (if it turns out to be good research).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: A humanist physicist; patient autonomy vs misinformation; self-injury; A RECIPE; healthcare violence and busness; Gaza; other items</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-01-21-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-01-21-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>Deep Dive: A humanist physicist; patient autonomy vs. misinformation; self-injury; A RECIPE (!); healthcare violence and busness; Gaza; other items</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: Ethics, psychiatry and industry funding; cool biodegradable coffins; Ubuntu; Chaplains replacing school counselors</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-01-12-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-01-12-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>“Is it okay for industry to fund the DSM-5-TR panel?; Is it okay for chaplains to replace school counselors?; Is it time to order your biodegradable coffin?; and, others!”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: Apple notifications and the Religious Right</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-04-21-deep-dive-scary-religious-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-04-21-deep-dive-scary-religious-right/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve liked my iPhone. Except for notifications. Google did them much better. But, that&amp;rsquo;s just an annoyance. The Religious Right and it&amp;rsquo;s efforts to create a love child with our political leaders is downright scary. We should be very scared. All of us. Even the good people who subscribe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: Weight, self-criticism, and compassion-focused therapy</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-03-25-weight-shame-water-kefir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-03-25-weight-shame-water-kefir/</guid>
      <description>Shame, self-criticism, and obesity go hand in hand. Also, my first posted recipe reference in our new website digs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dives: shame, smells, and shaming people</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-03-19-shame-smell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-03-19-shame-smell/</guid>
      <description>Shame drives us to great self-harm. Media is shame&amp;rsquo;s sledge hammer. Also, pay attention to the sense of smell!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: Lots more than I could put in a title</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-03-11_deep_dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-03-11_deep_dive/</guid>
      <description>This week we look at psychological well-being - including from the U.S. Surgeon General, paying attention to the experience of detransitioners, exposomics, silence and epigenetics, Buddhism (religion or not), and my bone to pick with the &lt;em&gt;Humanist Chaplaincy Network&lt;/em&gt; (I&amp;rsquo;m not picking any bones with humanist chaplains).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive for 2024-02-25: Was COVID worse than the flu? </title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-02-25-deeper-dive-covid-flu-worse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-02-25-deeper-dive-covid-flu-worse/</guid>
      <description>People who should have known to keep quiet until we had the data, told us that COVID was no worse than the flu. They were wrong</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: Articles on contemplative practices and near death experiences</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-02-17_deepdive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-02-17_deepdive/</guid>
      <description>This week we consider recent research on mindfulness showing distinct patterns of contemplative practive help well-being. We also look at an article on the death experience during CPR. Maybe we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t blow off those near-death experiences so quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: The Myers-Briggs Type Indicator</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-03-04-deep-dive-myers-briggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2023-03-04-deep-dive-myers-briggs/</guid>
      <description>The Myers-Briggs Type Indicator, many other purported personality measurements falls short in terms of accuracy. In the wrong hands, it can be dangerous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: PTSD; nature; wanting; meditation; COVID impact; expensive cars</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2022-12-12-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2022-12-12-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>Nurses protest use of AI; the importance of personal and cultural reconsideration on the importance of sleep; prosecution of medical errors; and Zionism and the Passover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: emotional PPE; stressors and suicide; pain and mindfulness; kindness; COVID</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2022-10-30-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2022-10-30-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>In this week&amp;rsquo;s Deep Dive, we talk about emotional PPE; stressors and suicide; pain and mindfulness; kindness; and, COVID</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive: False claims about mRNA vaccines</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2022-03-08-false-claims-about-mrna-vaccines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2022-03-08-false-claims-about-mrna-vaccines/</guid>
      <description>The Epoch Times made false claims about mRNA vaccines</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-11-13-christian-nationalism-and-public-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2024-11-13-christian-nationalism-and-public-schools/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>