<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Awareness on Worldwide Stew</title>
    <link>https://worldwidestew.com/tags/awareness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Awareness on Worldwide Stew</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 Worldwide Stew, aka Michael Davis.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:23:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://worldwidestew.com/tags/awareness/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Listening to your own Deep Space</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/media/2025-10-07-listening-to-your-own-deep-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/media/2025-10-07-listening-to-your-own-deep-space/</guid>
      <description>We just added a new podcast episode, Listening to Your Own Deep Space. This episode is available on Apple podcasts.
If you prefer to read my blog post that came out before the podcast, you can check it out here.
I like taking quizzes to see what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned. If you enjoy taking easy quizzes (which can also do something for your self-esteem), the blog post or listening to the podcast episode, check out what you learned here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to your own Deep Space</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-09-05-listening-to-your-own-deep-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 21:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-09-05-listening-to-your-own-deep-space/</guid>
      <description>You, too, have Deep Space. You should be listening to it Reader Note: If you prefer, you can listen to this on the Worldwide Stew podcast page. This episode is available on Apple podcasts. After reading this page or listening to the podcast episode, check out what you learned with a short quiz here.
Many years ago, Einstein predicted we should be able to hear gravitational waves: big events that happened in outer space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your ego is essential</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-09-03-your-ego-is-essential/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 20:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-09-03-your-ego-is-essential/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of your ego The ego is something we can&amp;rsquo;t see. But, even though we can&amp;rsquo;t see it, we can observe it in our own lives every day. Our fears, awareness of self, concerns about what the future holds, and what other people are getting are all evidence of our egos at work. We are defensive, afraid to apologize, and afraid to speak up because of our egos. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean the ego is bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checking in</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2024-09-29-checking-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2024-09-29-checking-in/</guid>
      <description>Describe your pain, the doctor said.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>