<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Society on Worldwide Stew</title>
    <link>https://worldwidestew.com/categories/society/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Society on Worldwide Stew</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 Worldwide Stew, aka Michael Davis.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 02:16:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://worldwidestew.com/categories/society/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Independence, wealth, and status</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-07-03-on-independence-wealth-and-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 02:16:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-07-03-on-independence-wealth-and-status/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s Indepenence Day in the United States. As a nation, the United States seems less independent than at any time in our history.
In this post, I wanted to talk about how a country&amp;rsquo;s economic policies promote or removes freedoms. This post starts with a policy that swept America away: Trickle-down Economics. Trickle-down economics came into public discussion during the United States Presidency of Ronald Reagan. It promised that great wealth trickles down to the poor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go to Your Room</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-06-16-go-to-your-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-06-16-go-to-your-room/</guid>
      <description>I suspect my Mom wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only parent who responded to her children&amp;rsquo;s loud disagreements and fighting by telling us to go to our rooms.
It was good advice. When we get caught up in fight (part of the fight, flight, faint network), the chemicals coursing through our bodies want to defend ourselves from fear of shame, embarrassment, and , occasionally, physical injury.
Often, the most mindful way of navigating our fear, anger, and doubt is to separate ourselves from the circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And then they came for me</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-06-14-and-then-they-came-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 17:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-06-14-and-then-they-came-for-me/</guid>
      <description>Pastor Martin Niemöller did what many Christians did when they saw the Third Reich systematically remove the rights of selected populations. Group by group, Hitler and his hinchmen took away the rights 1) of the press, 2) of educational institutions and their professors, 3) of races, 4) the mentally ill, 5) of dissidents, and of other groups.
Like all good religious people, he said nothing.
Then they came for him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gavin Newsome on the Trump Administration and Democracy</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2025-06-13-gavin-newsome-on-the-trump-administration-and-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2025-06-13-gavin-newsome-on-the-trump-administration-and-democracy/</guid>
      <description>When I started Worldwide Stew, I intended the Blog area of the site to be generally positive in tone. I would reserve the Opinion area of the site for news and opinions about science, health, politics, and fun stuff.
And then we ended up with what can only be called a fascist Administration(Merriam-Webster definition at the link). At this point, the scaffolding that held up any form of democracy is quickly eroding, like hurricane-force winds along the shoreline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Public Media</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2025-06-11-save-public-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 01:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2025-06-11-save-public-media/</guid>
      <description>If you live in the United States and can read this text, it&amp;rsquo;s possible that you learned some reading on Sesame Street. As you got older, you might have watched an episode of the science program Nova. As an adult, you may have watched news programming on the Evening News Hour. While it is fair to say that PBS coverage does tend to lean left of center; unlike other network news, however, PBS makes a concerted effort to fairly cover multiple sides of the issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beliefs Worth Examining</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-05-10-beliefs-worth-examining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-05-10-beliefs-worth-examining/</guid>
      <description>What would your belief system - your religion and politics, for example - have to do to cause you to reject it? It&amp;rsquo;s a question for our ideology-driven times.
Decades ago I believed in almost every facet of the Christian Nationalist dream, including their beliefs about sexuality. I ignored the human experience, following ideology instead. Then, as a chaplain in training, I sat by a gay man who lost his partner moments before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Obligations of Witnessing</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-05-10-the-obligations-of-witnessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 00:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-05-10-the-obligations-of-witnessing/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago, I worked in a little religious school. One of the children could barely speak. She had many siblings. She came to school with bruises. One day she accidentally fell out of the car. I told the principal that we should report the situation. I was told that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t our business and that reporting them to government authorities wasn&amp;rsquo;t right. I still anonymously reported them. My employment ended soon thereafter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Satisfaction Guaranteed or Your Money Back</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-04-28-2025-04-28satisfaction-or-your-money-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 02:24:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-04-28-2025-04-28satisfaction-or-your-money-back/</guid>
      <description>Satisfaction guaranteed or your money back.
When someone says, Satisfaction guaranteed or your money back they are upping the value of their promise. They are saying, You have nothing to lose.
But, even if you are able to get your money back, you&amp;rsquo;ve still lost something: time and trust. Broken trust steadily erodes our lives and connections. The return of our money can&amp;rsquo;t return the time and hope for a resolution to our problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Wisdom Beyond Desperation</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-02-25-finding-wisdom-beyond-desperation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 13:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-02-25-finding-wisdom-beyond-desperation/</guid>
      <description>When we lead from wisdom, we must first recognize when desire transforms into craving.
My vision for creating meaningful mindfulness opportunities keeps me motivated, but I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed how easily genuine passion can transform into an anxious urgency—a shift that rarely allows for clear discernment or thoughtful decision-making.
Operating from desperation narrows our vision. It tempts us toward shortcuts, clouds our understanding, and blinds us to others&amp;rsquo; authentic motives and needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No, Sir</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-02-14-no-sir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 22:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-02-14-no-sir/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I haven&amp;rsquo;t in the 23 years that I have been in the uniformed services of the USA ever violated an order, not one.&amp;rdquo; - Oliver North, Iran-Contra Affair testimony.
I grew up in a military family. Yes, Sir. No, Sir. You were supposed to follow orders. Not the orders you chose, but all orders. Perhaps Oliver North - who chose to follow all orders - wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have ended up testifying before Cngress in the Iran-Contra Scandal if he had chosen to disobey illegal orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home is where the Toad is</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-29-home-is-where-the-toad-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:23:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-29-home-is-where-the-toad-is/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-reflection-on-home-respect-safety-and-artificial-intelligence&#34;&gt;A reflection on home, respect, safety, and artificial intelligence.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this post I hope to do two things. I want to write about home. And Toads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on a quest to find a happy quotation to seal into a home being built by a friend. &lt;em&gt;Do you have a good blessing, verse, or prayer?&lt;/em&gt;  Where should I go but my favorite AI, &lt;a href=&#34;https://claude.ai&#34;&gt;Claude.ai&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you for a courteous No</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-20-thank-you-for-a-courteous-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 21:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-20-thank-you-for-a-courteous-no/</guid>
      <description>How we respond to the needs of others dictates our futures. We are all ready for a fight. Is this really the only option?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI for the Rest of Us: A Hands-On Workshop</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/events/2025-03-20-ai-for-the-rest-of-us-a-hands-on-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 18:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/events/2025-03-20-ai-for-the-rest-of-us-a-hands-on-workshop/</guid>
      <description>🚀 REGISTRATION for the May session has closed. New sessions will coming in July and August 2025. I&amp;rsquo;ll announce the dates soon.
🚀 ANNOUNCING TWO SESSIONS: &amp;ldquo;AI for the Rest of Us&amp;rdquo; - A Hands-On Workshop
&amp;ldquo;AI for the Rest of Us&amp;rdquo; - It&amp;rsquo;s Not Just About Work Tasks
I&amp;rsquo;ve been reflecting on what makes our upcoming AI workshop truly special, and I wanted to share more about the journey we&amp;rsquo;ll take together&amp;hellip; This isn&amp;rsquo;t just another &amp;ldquo;productivity hack&amp;rdquo; class.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>