<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inspiration on Worldwide Stew</title>
    <link>https://worldwidestew.com/categories/inspiration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inspiration on Worldwide Stew</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 Worldwide Stew, aka Michael Davis.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:15:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://worldwidestew.com/categories/inspiration/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Go to Your Room</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-06-16-go-to-your-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-06-16-go-to-your-room/</guid>
      <description>I suspect my Mom wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only parent who responded to her children&amp;rsquo;s loud disagreements and fighting by telling us to go to our rooms.
It was good advice. When we get caught up in fight (part of the fight, flight, faint network), the chemicals coursing through our bodies want to defend ourselves from fear of shame, embarrassment, and , occasionally, physical injury.
Often, the most mindful way of navigating our fear, anger, and doubt is to separate ourselves from the circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distractions, attention, and focus</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-05-15-distractions-attention-and-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 01:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-05-15-distractions-attention-and-focus/</guid>
      <description>It was a beautiful winter night to take our dog out for a walk. Looking toward the west I saw the planetary alignment my wife had told me about earlier that day. I immediately pulled out my phone to capture a picture. But, the picture didn&amp;rsquo;t look just right. So, I opened a browser window to see what settings to adjust for night shots. I must have messed with my phone settings for ten minutes before the ridiculousness of the situation dawned on me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What matters to me?</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-04-02-what-is-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 19:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-04-02-what-is-your-work/</guid>
      <description>Asking Why am I here? is probably wasting time. It&amp;rsquo;s like a termite trying to eat a sequoia. It&amp;rsquo;s too big and carries little action.
You&amp;rsquo;re probably better off asking two other questions:
What things matter to me? What things matter to the people I care about? There&amp;rsquo;s a host of other questions you can (and should) ask. But these are awesome places to start or reset. Begin with either one, then tackle the other one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being conscientious isn&#39;t a moral virtue.</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-03-10-being-conscientious-isnt-a-moral-virtue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-03-10-being-conscientious-isnt-a-moral-virtue/</guid>
      <description>Working hard - being conscientious - is not a moral virtue. It&amp;rsquo;s not enough.
The grade on your assignment has nothing to do with how hard you worked on it. You get a grade dependent on your answers being correct. If we didn&amp;rsquo;t answer the questions, show our work, or do the work, the teacher won&amp;rsquo;t care. The point wasn&amp;rsquo;t to work hard. The point of the assignment is to get the correct answer and show your work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deputized on Ash Wednesday</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-03-05-deputized-to-impose-ashes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 22:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-03-05-deputized-to-impose-ashes/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s Ash Wednesday. I feel a little sad about that. Why? When I think of Ash Wednesday, here&amp;rsquo;s the thing I remember most.
I was a chaplain at Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Heart and Vascular Hospital in Dallas. Even though I wasn&amp;rsquo;t Catholic, each Ash Wednesday I was deputized to impose Ashes on the foreheads of anyone who wanted them. I received Ashes and then was deputized to impose them on others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Wisdom Beyond Desperation</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-02-25-finding-wisdom-beyond-desperation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 13:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-02-25-finding-wisdom-beyond-desperation/</guid>
      <description>When we lead from wisdom, we must first recognize when desire transforms into craving.
My vision for creating meaningful mindfulness opportunities keeps me motivated, but I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed how easily genuine passion can transform into an anxious urgency—a shift that rarely allows for clear discernment or thoughtful decision-making.
Operating from desperation narrows our vision. It tempts us toward shortcuts, clouds our understanding, and blinds us to others&amp;rsquo; authentic motives and needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veni Vidi Vici</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-02-02-veni-vidi-vici/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 03:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-02-02-veni-vidi-vici/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Veni, Vidi, Vici&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This phrase, Latin for &lt;em&gt;I came, I saw, I conquered&lt;/em&gt;, was reportedly uttered by Julius Caesar. At least that&amp;rsquo;s what my high school Latin teacher and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Veni,_vidi,_vici&#34;&gt;Wikipedia say&lt;/a&gt;. Wikipedia says it refers to a &lt;em&gt;swift, decisive victory.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Saturday Night Monster</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-22-the-saturday-night-fridge-raid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 22:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-22-the-saturday-night-fridge-raid/</guid>
      <description>The Saturday Night Monster Late on Saturday nights, the most frightening monster of all enters our home. It drags me to the fridge, seizing my hands and coercing them into into the freezer section. Resistance, as they say, is futile. Before I know it, I&amp;rsquo;ve succumbed to it&amp;rsquo;s cruel overtures.
If I were more mindful about the Saturday Night Monster,
Or, if I wanted to be more mindful about the Saturday Night Monster,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are beautiful</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-20-you-are-beautiful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 02:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-20-you-are-beautiful/</guid>
      <description>I was passing through the living room. An advertisement was on the television. I feel a special contempt for these kinds of ads. A woman had used some kind of special formula.&amp;quot; As a result os using the preparation she said, I was beautiful.&amp;quot;
No, dear lady. To the extent you&amp;rsquo;re beautiful, it comes from the inside.
In the many years I cared for very sick people, I saw many of them when they regarded themselves as ugly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is a test</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-17-this-is-a-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 21:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-17-this-is-a-test/</guid>
      <description>We all need to try new things. And, make mistakes. Then, try again.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>