<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on Worldwide Stew</title>
    <link>https://worldwidestew.com/tags/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on Worldwide Stew</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 Worldwide Stew, aka Michael Davis.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:23:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://worldwidestew.com/tags/science/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Listening to your own Deep Space</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/media/2025-10-07-listening-to-your-own-deep-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/media/2025-10-07-listening-to-your-own-deep-space/</guid>
      <description>We just added a new podcast episode, Listening to Your Own Deep Space. This episode is available on Apple podcasts.
If you prefer to read my blog post that came out before the podcast, you can check it out here.
I like taking quizzes to see what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned. If you enjoy taking easy quizzes (which can also do something for your self-esteem), the blog post or listening to the podcast episode, check out what you learned here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gossamer Cloak</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-09-20-the-gossamer-cloak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 20:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-09-20-the-gossamer-cloak/</guid>
      <description>I beg you tp keep reading for just a minute.
This coming week NASA plans to send three projects into space. One of them is the Carruthers Geocorona Observatory. This mission wants to better understand our outer atmosphere. This knowledge will help us understand changes that occur in the area just before we get to &amp;ldquo;outer space.&amp;rdquo; Scientists call this the geocorona. Scientists love big words. And, Of course, they need a very specific definition they all know and understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your ego is essential</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-09-03-your-ego-is-essential/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 20:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-09-03-your-ego-is-essential/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of your ego The ego is something we can&amp;rsquo;t see. But, even though we can&amp;rsquo;t see it, we can observe it in our own lives every day. Our fears, awareness of self, concerns about what the future holds, and what other people are getting are all evidence of our egos at work. We are defensive, afraid to apologize, and afraid to speak up because of our egos. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean the ego is bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beliefs Worth Examining</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-05-10-beliefs-worth-examining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-05-10-beliefs-worth-examining/</guid>
      <description>What would your belief system - your religion and politics, for example - have to do to cause you to reject it? It&amp;rsquo;s a question for our ideology-driven times.
Decades ago I believed in almost every facet of the Christian Nationalist dream, including their beliefs about sexuality. I ignored the human experience, following ideology instead. Then, as a chaplain in training, I sat by a gay man who lost his partner moments before.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>