<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Service on Worldwide Stew</title>
    <link>https://worldwidestew.com/tags/service/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Service on Worldwide Stew</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 Worldwide Stew, aka Michael Davis.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:54:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://worldwidestew.com/tags/service/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gavin Newsome on the Trump Administration and Democracy</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2025-06-13-gavin-newsome-on-the-trump-administration-and-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/editorial/2025-06-13-gavin-newsome-on-the-trump-administration-and-democracy/</guid>
      <description>When I started Worldwide Stew, I intended the Blog area of the site to be generally positive in tone. I would reserve the Opinion area of the site for news and opinions about science, health, politics, and fun stuff.
And then we ended up with what can only be called a fascist Administration(Merriam-Webster definition at the link). At this point, the scaffolding that held up any form of democracy is quickly eroding, like hurricane-force winds along the shoreline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What matters to me?</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-04-02-what-is-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 19:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-04-02-what-is-your-work/</guid>
      <description>Asking Why am I here? is probably wasting time. It&amp;rsquo;s like a termite trying to eat a sequoia. It&amp;rsquo;s too big and carries little action.
You&amp;rsquo;re probably better off asking two other questions:
What things matter to me? What things matter to the people I care about? There&amp;rsquo;s a host of other questions you can (and should) ask. But these are awesome places to start or reset. Begin with either one, then tackle the other one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deputized on Ash Wednesday</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-03-05-deputized-to-impose-ashes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 22:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-03-05-deputized-to-impose-ashes/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s Ash Wednesday. I feel a little sad about that. Why? When I think of Ash Wednesday, here&amp;rsquo;s the thing I remember most.
I was a chaplain at Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Heart and Vascular Hospital in Dallas. Even though I wasn&amp;rsquo;t Catholic, each Ash Wednesday I was deputized to impose Ashes on the foreheads of anyone who wanted them. I received Ashes and then was deputized to impose them on others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>