<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Media on Worldwide Stew</title>
    <link>https://worldwidestew.com/media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Media on Worldwide Stew</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 Worldwide Stew, aka Michael Davis.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:23:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://worldwidestew.com/media/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Listening to your own Deep Space</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/media/2025-10-07-listening-to-your-own-deep-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/media/2025-10-07-listening-to-your-own-deep-space/</guid>
      <description>We just added a new podcast episode, Listening to Your Own Deep Space. This episode is available on Apple podcasts.
If you prefer to read my blog post that came out before the podcast, you can check it out here.
I like taking quizzes to see what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned. If you enjoy taking easy quizzes (which can also do something for your self-esteem), the blog post or listening to the podcast episode, check out what you learned here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief meditation for Parkinsons Disease</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/media/2025-08-19-a-brief-meditation-for-parkinsons-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/media/2025-08-19-a-brief-meditation-for-parkinsons-disease/</guid>
      <description>This is a transcript of my Self-Acceptance Meditation This meditation is a collaboration with Claude.ai.
Hi, this is Mike Davis. I am the host of the Worldwide Stew podcast and WorldwideStew.com. This is a focused effort to try to provide some hopefully helpful meditation, brief ones, for those with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease. I hope this helps. Thanks for listening. So I want to welcome you to this gentle meditation for self-acceptance. However you arrived here today, at this moment, sitting, lying down, in a wheelchair, you&amp;rsquo;ve made it to this moment and that takes incredible courage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel, health, and generations with Anthony Nguyen</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/media/2024-08-27-anthony-nguyen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/media/2024-08-27-anthony-nguyen/</guid>
      <description>In this first interview epidode of the Worldwide Stew podcast, I interviewed my friend, Anthony Nguyen, BSN, RN. He talks about travel (joys and travails), children, aging, the elderly, how to look at travel, and the role of chaaplains in acute pain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>