<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strength on Worldwide Stew</title>
    <link>https://worldwidestew.com/categories/strength/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strength on Worldwide Stew</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 Worldwide Stew, aka Michael Davis.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 23:36:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://worldwidestew.com/categories/strength/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Make do with what you have</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-12-19-making-do-with-what-you-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 23:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-12-19-making-do-with-what-you-have/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re asked to fetch a ball. Without arms or legs. I&amp;rsquo;m sorry. I can&amp;rsquo;t. In fact, the very fact that you ask is is insulting and cruel.
But, is it possible we could, at the very least, contemplate working it out: how could I fetch a ball without arms or legs?
We&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that in a second.
Do animals play? Yes, it seems some do. But, you have to take into account the definition of play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief meditation for Parkinsons Disease</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/media/2025-08-19-a-brief-meditation-for-parkinsons-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/media/2025-08-19-a-brief-meditation-for-parkinsons-disease/</guid>
      <description>This is a transcript of my Self-Acceptance Meditation This meditation is a collaboration with Claude.ai.
Hi, this is Mike Davis. I am the host of the Worldwide Stew podcast and WorldwideStew.com. This is a focused effort to try to provide some hopefully helpful meditation, brief ones, for those with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease. I hope this helps. Thanks for listening. So I want to welcome you to this gentle meditation for self-acceptance. However you arrived here today, at this moment, sitting, lying down, in a wheelchair, you&amp;rsquo;ve made it to this moment and that takes incredible courage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deputized on Ash Wednesday</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-03-05-deputized-to-impose-ashes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 22:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-03-05-deputized-to-impose-ashes/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s Ash Wednesday. I feel a little sad about that. Why? When I think of Ash Wednesday, here&amp;rsquo;s the thing I remember most.
I was a chaplain at Baylor Scott &amp;amp; White Heart and Vascular Hospital in Dallas. Even though I wasn&amp;rsquo;t Catholic, each Ash Wednesday I was deputized to impose Ashes on the foreheads of anyone who wanted them. I received Ashes and then was deputized to impose them on others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Saturday Night Monster</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-22-the-saturday-night-fridge-raid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 22:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-22-the-saturday-night-fridge-raid/</guid>
      <description>The Saturday Night Monster Late on Saturday nights, the most frightening monster of all enters our home. It drags me to the fridge, seizing my hands and coercing them into into the freezer section. Resistance, as they say, is futile. Before I know it, I&amp;rsquo;ve succumbed to it&amp;rsquo;s cruel overtures.
If I were more mindful about the Saturday Night Monster,
Or, if I wanted to be more mindful about the Saturday Night Monster,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are beautiful</title>
      <link>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-20-you-are-beautiful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 02:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwidestew.com/blog/2025-01-20-you-are-beautiful/</guid>
      <description>I was passing through the living room. An advertisement was on the television. I feel a special contempt for these kinds of ads. A woman had used some kind of special formula.&amp;quot; As a result os using the preparation she said, I was beautiful.&amp;quot;
No, dear lady. To the extent you&amp;rsquo;re beautiful, it comes from the inside.
In the many years I cared for very sick people, I saw many of them when they regarded themselves as ugly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>